Finding Aid for YMCA of Metropolitan Detroit, Metropolitan Offices records, 1877-2012
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Visual materials
  - Photographs
    - Public Relations Reference File 1976-2005, undated
      - Topical
        - Original YMCA building (Box 8)
        - Physical fitness (Box 9)
        - Pontiac YMCA (Box 9)
        - Portraits, 3 folders (Box 9)
          (include some earlier personages)
        - Postcards of Downtown Y and other buildings (Box 9)
        - Senior Wellness (Box 9)
        - You Belong (Box 9)
        - Panoramic group portraits of YMCA banquets (Folder 1)
        - Basketball teams 1908-1910 (Box 10)
        - Branches buildings (exteriors) circa 1950s, undated (Box 10)
          (include old and new Y sketches)
        - Detroit YMCA floor and site plans 2002 (Box 10)
        - Like Now: for supporting Youth (Box 10)
- Miscellaneous
  - Artifacts: baseball, banner, patches, etc. (Box 13)
- Scrapbooks, 1936-1973 (some gaps)
  The scrapbooks contain clippings about the various YMCA branches from Detroit newspapers. The scrapbooks for the years 1936 to 1945 reflect an incredibly thorough search of all newspapers in the metropolitan Detroit area and have the clippings arranged chronologically with a color-coded heading identifying which branch is mentioned. These scrapbooks appear to have been created by the public relations department at about the same time as the photograph file as both reflect a department dedicated to raising the profile of the YMCA. The 1957-1962 scrapbooks, which came from the 2006 accession, contain newspaper clippings, programs from various fund raising events, expansion program forms, and reservation forms. The last scrapbook covers the early 1970s and reflects the YMCA's concern with family fitness in suburban Detroit.
  - 1936, 2 volumes
    - 1936 (Volume 1)
    - 1936 (Volume 2)
      (continued)
  - 1937, 2 volumes
    - 1937 (Volume 3)
    - 1937 (Volume 4)
  - 1938, 2 volumes
    - 1938 (Volume 5)
    - 1938 (Volume 6)
  - 1939, 2 volumes
    - 1939 (Volume 7)
    - 1939 (Volume 8)
  - 1940, 2 volumes
    - 1940 (Volume 9)
    - 1940 (Volume 10)
  - 1941, 2 volumes
    - 1941 (Volume 11)
    - 1941 (Volume 12)
  - 1942 (Volume 13)
  - 1943 (Volume 14)
  - 1944 (Volume 15)
  - 1945 (unbound) (Volume 16)
  - 1949-1958, 1965-1969, 1971-1981 (Volume 21)
  - 1957-1960 (Volume 18)
  - 1961 (Volume 19)
  - 1961-1962 (Volume 20)
  - 1971-1973 (Volume 17)